Idlewild is a crime, drama, music film directed by Bryan Barber.
A reticent piano player Percival, along with Rooster, his flamboyant lead performer and manager, struggle to keep
their speakeasy, in the Prohibition-era South, out of the hands of gangsters who want to take it over.
Percival, played by André 3000.
Rooster, played by Big Boi.
Angel, played by Paula Patton.
Trumpy, played by Terrence Howard.
Ace, played by Faizon Love.
Zora, played by Malinda Williams.
Idlewild is a 2006 American musical drama film
written and directed by Bryan Barber.
The film stars André 3000 and Big Boi of the hip hop duo Outkast and features musical
numbers that were written, produced and chiefly performed by the group.
Idlewild contrasts the group's hip-hop, funk, and soul sound against a story based on a juke joint
in the fictional town of Idlewild, during the Great Depression in Georgia in 1935.
Distributed by Universal Pictures, the film is an HBO Films
co-production alongside Mosaic Media Group and Forensic Films.
It features an ensemble cast including Terrence Howard, Paula Jai Parker, Paula Patton, Cicely Tyson, Ben Vereen, Patti
LaBelle, Ving Rhames, Macy Gray, Faizon Love, Bruce Bruce, Malinda Williams, Jackie Long and Bill Nunn.
Idlewild received mixed reviews from critics and
grossed $12.6 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of piano lessons, mortician,
tied to chair, song and dance, fisticuffs.
The tone is emotional.